Jean Pamphile

jean.pamphile@carleton.ca | 613.834.7586 | Ottawa, ON https://jpamphile.github.io | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeanpamphile

Summary

COMPUTER SCIENCE STUDENT WITH NEARLY 15 YEARS WORK EXPERIENCE IN PUBLIC HEALTH MOTIVATED TO FURTHER MY THEORETICAL AND PRACTICAL SKILLS IN QUALITY DESIGN, IMPLEMENTATION AND TESTING OF SOFTWARE AND HARDWARE ARCHITECTURES. WHEN I CODE, I DIVIDE AND CONQUER SO THAT WHAT I BUILD CAN UNITE AND HELP PROSPER. EXCEPTIONAL INTERPERSONAL SKILLS WITH THE DETERMINATION TO RESOLVE COMPLEX COMPUTING CHALLENGES. I LOOK TO IMPROVE BUSINESS FUNCTIONALITY AND POSITIVELY IMPACT THE BOTTOM LINE. DEMONSTRATED ABILITY TO QUICKLY LEARN, APPLY NEW CONCEPTS, ADAPT TO CHANGE, AND COMMUNICATE FLUENTLY IN BOTH FRENCH AND ENGLISH.

Work Experience

Public Health Promoter

December 2005 - Present

Eastern Ontario Health Unit, Casselman, ON

http://www.eohu.ca/

As part of the Chronic Disease Prevention and Injury Prevention Substance Misuse teams - December 2010 to present;

- Analyzed data to support the implementation of public health initiatives to impre the lives of youth and families.
- Developed data gathering tools and reports for with community partners based on the latest demographic trends.

As a Heart Health Project Officer coordinating the Ontario Heart Health Project - December 2005 to December 2010;

- Managed a portfolio of grants totaling \$425k over 5 years, including agreements with the Ministry of Health, the EOHU and local stakeholders.
- Provided public health direction and oversight to over 50 community health organizations throughout the five counties of Eastern Ontario.

Professor

May 2010 - May 2012

Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON

http://www.algonquincollege.com

- Supported the Department of Fitness & Lifestyle Management in teaching Exercise Counselling, developing innovative curricula and materials.
- Developed assessment measures utilizing various technology platforms ensuring successful, engaging education to a diverse student population.

1/3

Mens College Soccer Head Coach

May 2006 - December 2012

College La Cite, Ottawa, ON

http://www.mescoyotes.ca/

To ensure a sustainable and successful mens soccer program.

https://jpamphile.github.io/cv/

- Implemented recruiting strategies for elite provincial-level student-athletes in Eastern Ontario, Toronto and Ottawa-Gatineau region.
- Managed training sessions and game tactics for weekly fixtures.
- Awarded 2010 Ontario Collegiate Athletic Association (OCAA) East Coach Of The Year for team's first post-season appearance.

Coding Projects

"Where In The World Is Carmen SanDiego?" - CLI Edition

http://jpamphile.github.io/

 Developed command line version of the popular show and vidoe game highlighting my skills in Object-Oriented Design and Programming in Java. With the guidance of Professor Jason Hinek, Carleton University - December 2017

"rankYouVeryMuch"

https://jpamphile.github.io/

Developed command line program which in fact helped me prioritize my weekly tasks and goals. This projects highlights my skills in function prototyping and implementation of a data structure/collection in Python. With the guidance of Professor Dave McKenney, Carleton University - June 2017

Sport & Health "Performance Analysis Of A Swim Coach: A Single-Subject Case Study"

Research Experience https://jpamphile.github.io/

 Developed and implemented a methodology based on video analysis and technology to collect and analyze behavioural data of an swim coach during to help improve knowledge transfer processes to swimmers - December 2005

"Qualitative Examination of Exercise Barriers and Facilitators in Maintenance Phase of a Randomized Exercise Trial for People with Type 2 Diabetes."

https://jpamphile.github.io/

- Provided data collection services for Dr. Michelle Fortier's Exercise Psychology research laboratory at the University of Ottawa.
- Capstick, G., Tulloch, H., Fortier, M. & Pamphile, J. (2004). Qualitative Examination of Exercise Barriers and Facilitators in the Maintenance Phase of a Randomized Exercise Trial for people With Type 2 Diabetes. Canadian Psychology, 45 (2a), 147.

Education

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

September 2016 - Present Bachelor of Computer Science

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON

September 2004 - December 2005

Master of Human Kinetics - Psychology of Physical Activity & Sport

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON

September 2004 - December 2005

Bachelor of Social Sciences - Honours in Sociology, Minor in Leisure Studies

Interests

Sports and Health Data Analysis • Artificial Intelligence • Software Design and Engineering • UI and UX • Artificial Intelligence • Internet of Things (IoT) • Software Delivery Process • Eastern

https://jpamphile.github.io/cv/

Ontario Physical Activity Network Chair (2016-2018) • Ontario Soccer Association Grade 8 Referee • Collector of cufflinks from around the world.

https://jpamphile.github.io/cv/ 3/3